<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.davmail.DavMail.desktop</id>
  <name>DavMail</name>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <summary>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Ever wanted to get rid of Outlook ? DavMail is a
      POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP exchange gateway allowing
      users to use any mail/calendar client (e.g. Thunderbird with
      Lightning or Apple iCal) with an Exchange server, even from the
      internet or behind a firewall through Outlook Web
      Access. DavMail now includes an LDAP gateway to Exchange global
      address book and user personal contacts to allow recipient
      address completion in mail compose window and full calendar
      support with attendees free/busy display. The main goal of
      DavMail is to provide standard compliant protocols in front of
      proprietary Exchange. This means LDAP for address book, SMTP to
      send messages, IMAP to browse messages on the server in any
      folder, POP to retrieve inbox messages only and Caldav for
      calendar support. Thus any standard compliant client can be used
      with Microsoft Exchange. DavMail gateway is implemented in java
      and should run on any platform. Releases are tested on Windows,
      Linux (Ubuntu) and Mac OSX. Tray does not work on MacOS and is
      replaced with a full frame. Tested successfully with the Iphone
      (gateway running on a server).
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://davmail.sourceforge.net</url>
  <url type="donation">https://sourceforge.net/donate/index.php?group_id=184600</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://screenshots.debian.net/screenshots/000/015/485/large.png</image>
      <image>http://davmail.sourceforge.net/images/davmailArchitecture.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0</project_license>
  <developer_name>Mickaël Guessant</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="5.2.0" date="2019-02-11">
      <description>
        <p>
            Includes improved ADFS compatibility and support Okta authentication in interactive mode,
            a fix for Thunderbird dismiss issue, a few LDAP and IMAP enhancements (TRYCREATE support).
            Also upgraded libraries to prepare HttpClient 4 upgrade.

            ###EWS:
            - EWS: improve O365 mode handling, force url
            - EWS: detect Okta authentication and explicitly fail in this case with O365Authenticator
            - EWS: O365StoredTokenAuthenticator test case
            - EWS: allow cross domain requests for Okta form support in O365Interactive mode
            - EWS: try to fix #702, add login.srf to OpenJFX workaround
            - EWS: Remove Jetbrains only annotation
            - EWS: Fix O365 device login check
            - EWS: cleanup from audit
            - EWS: Another step in O365 device login
            - EWS: detect devicelogin after O365 ADFS authentication, try to follow redirect
            - EWS: adjust 0365Token log statement level

            ###Caldav:
            - Caldav: explicitly detect Thunderbird dismiss/snooze events to update only mozilla custom properties
            - Caldav: fix #705 daily recurrence issue
            - Caldav: experimental, return created item URL in Location header
            - Caldav: enable isorganizer field
            - Caldav: adjust isOrganizer check (again) to work on all Exchange server versions
            - Caldav: workaround for missing DTEND in event, avoid NullPointerException
            - Caldav: fix recurrence options and implement interval over EWS
            - Caldav: fix montly recurrence handling

            ###IMAP:
            - IMAP: fix #704 implement [TRYCREATE] on folder not found
            - IMAP: Fix FETCH RFC822 request for python imap client.
            - IMAP: Additional fix for slash in folder name

            ###Carddav:
            - Carddav: fix regression, override getAllContacts to list contacts and distribution lists

            ###LDAP:
            - LDAP: cleanup from audit and support simple rdn authentication, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/18
            - LDAP: implement hassubordinates attribute
            - LDAP: fix contact filter over EWS
            - LDAP: fix dn authentication, fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/18
            - LDAP: improve dn authentication, fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/18
            - LDAP: implement dn authentication, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/18
            - LDAP: test case for dn authentication, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/18
            - LDAP: encode uid value in dn, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/18
            - LDAP: add mappings for HomePhone and Pager attributes

            ###Documentation
            - Doc: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/21
            - Doc: Improve documentation of client connection timeout, merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/20
            - Doc: remove alt from OpenHub link
            - Doc: merge documentation provided by Geert Stappers
            - Doc: Update roadmap
            - Doc: update README.md
            - Doc: document Android configuration with a DavMail server
            - Doc: prepare android setup instructions
            - Doc: improve download link in README.md
            - Doc: update Debian package description
            - Doc: fix openhub link

            ###HTTP:
            - HTTP: switch from URIUtil to URIBuilder in Caldav test cases
            - HTTP: more Caldav test cases with HttpClientAdapter
            - HTTP: implement caldav report and search test case with HttpClientAdapter
            - HTTP: implement Dav request in HttpClient 4 adapter
            - HTTP: improve HttpClient 4 adapter, detect relative url
            - HTTP: implement HttpClientAdapter follow redirects and parse username
            - HTTP: first HttpClientAdapter draft
            - HTTP: include HttpClient 4
            - Update commons-codec to 1.11 (prepare HttpClient 4 migration)
            - HTTP: test HttpClient 4 connection pool management and expiration
            - HTTP: More HttpClient 4 test cases for authentication, proxy, redirects and URI handling
            - HTTP: Basic HttpClient 4 test cases
            - Update jackrabbit to 2.14.6 (latest version to support httpclient 3.1

            ###Linux:
            - Linux: adjust tray icon for XFCE and KDE
            - Linux: try to adjust tray icon for XFCE
            - Linux: fix swt jar exists test in launch script
            - Linux: fix SWT version in POM and update description
            - Linux: adjust systemd service to rhel/centos
            - Add DavMail systemd service in spec file
            - Linux: fix compatibility with older distributions
            - SWT: Improve code to make it compatible with older SWT libraries in Ubuntu 18.
            - Linux: fix spec file regression

            ###Maven:
            - Maven: reenable site plugins in pom
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
