<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.davmail.DavMail.desktop</id>
  <name>DavMail</name>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <summary>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Ever wanted to get rid of Outlook ? DavMail is a
      POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP exchange gateway allowing
      users to use any mail/calendar client (e.g. Thunderbird with
      Lightning or Apple iCal) with an Exchange server, even from the
      internet or behind a firewall through Outlook Web
      Access. DavMail now includes an LDAP gateway to Exchange global
      address book and user personal contacts to allow recipient
      address completion in mail compose window and full calendar
      support with attendees free/busy display. The main goal of
      DavMail is to provide standard compliant protocols in front of
      proprietary Exchange. This means LDAP for address book, SMTP to
      send messages, IMAP to browse messages on the server in any
      folder, POP to retrieve inbox messages only and Caldav for
      calendar support. Thus any standard compliant client can be used
      with Microsoft Exchange. DavMail gateway is implemented in java
      and should run on any platform. Releases are tested on Windows,
      Linux (Ubuntu) and Mac OSX. Tray does not work on MacOS and is
      replaced with a full frame. Tested successfully with the Iphone
      (gateway running on a server).
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://davmail.sourceforge.net</url>
  <url type="donation">https://sourceforge.net/donate/index.php?group_id=184600</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://screenshots.debian.net/screenshots/000/015/485/large.png</image>
      <image>http://davmail.sourceforge.net/images/davmailArchitecture.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0</project_license>
  <developer_name>Mickaël Guessant</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="5.1.0" date="2018-12-18">
      <description>
        <p>
Much improved interactive O365 authentication with OpenJFX bug workaround,
experimental stored Oauth refresh token support. More Linux distributions were tested
to make DavMail work with recent KDE and Gnome environments.

### EWS:
- EWS: more progress on ADFS authentication
- EWS: cleanup warning message
- EWS: experimental, implement davmail.oauth.persistToken to store Oauth refresh token
- EWS: make progress on O365 ADFS authentication, fix method
- EWS: stored token authentication, load token by username
- EWS: make progress on O365 ADFS authentication, enable NTLM and pass credentials
- EWS: O365 authentication, set resource url on token refresh
- EWS: set default access token expiration
- EWS: implement stored access token in addition to refresh token (will only last one hour)
- EWS: experimental, load Oauth refresh token from setting davmail.oauth.refreshToken
- EWS: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/15 empty domain in NTLM authentication
- EWS: revert to 4.9.0 behavior for EWS mode
- EWS: fix regression in token handling
- EWS: allow urn protocol in O365 authenticator
- EWS: fix regression when main authentication relies on OWA and/or ADFS
- EWS: check for errors in returned json token
- EWS: Fix warning message
- EWS: workaround for JavaFX bug, add one more URL
- EWS: call setAlwaysOnTop(true); on page load success
- EWS: in addition to requestFocus, call toFront
- EWS: workaround for JavaFX bug, handle more methods in connection wrapper
- EWS: workaround for JavaFX bug, handle post requests
- EWS: workaround for JavaFX bug, add additional microsoft url
- EWS: workaround for JavaFX bug, fix java 8 regression
- EWS: Add export compiler arg java.base/sun.net.www.protocol.https for webview bug workaround
- EWS: improve interactive authenticator focus handling and remove reflection calls
- EWS: workaround for JavaFX bug, use reflection to avoid java 9 errors
- EWS: workaround for JavaFX bug, drop reference to internal sun class HttpsURLConnectionImpl
- EWS: workaround for JavaFX bug, disable integrity check on external resources in O365 authentication form
- EWS: javafx test can also trigger NoClassDefFoundError
- EWS: Rename JSLogger
- EWS: improve O365 interactive error handling
- EWS: override console.log to send error messages to Log4J
- EWS: More EWS test cases
- EWS: new authenticator test cases
- EWS: detect when user settings validation is required by Office 365
- EWS: detect manual window close event
- EWS: Make sure we close frame on timeout, improve error message
- EWS: refactor O365 authenticator to do all gui calls in Swing thread
- EWS: cleanup from audit
- EWS: encode slash inside folder names
- EWS: convert date without SimpleDateFormat during load messages to improve performance and reduce memory footprint
- EWS: Send authentication failed instead of generic error in case of username mismatch in O365Authenticator

### Documentation:
- Doc: update project description in README.md
- Doc: update project description
- Doc: adjust IntelliJ link according to JetBrains recommendation
- Doc: revert openhub change, was a target side issue
- Doc: add YourKit Java Profiler logo to home page
- Doc: improve IntelliJ IDEA home page logo
- Doc: fix swt gtk version in documentation
- Doc: fix openhub link
- Doc: add link to https://apps.dev.microsoft.com/
- Doc: direct link to latest release package download list in README.md
- Doc: fix link in server setup documentation

### OSX:
- OSX: upgrade universalJavaApplicationStub to 3.0.4

### Linux:
- Linux: prepare systemd service
- Linux: missing openjfx dependency
- Linux: set cross platform look and feel on Linux, except is swing.defaultlaf is set
- Linux: enable anti aliasing in GUI
- Linux: improve launch scripts to handle more cases (OpenJDK 11 with or without SWT)
- Linux: remove swt4 suggests and revert gtk force, does not work under debian sid
- Linux: Force gtk version no longer required with cross platform look and feel
- Linux: use hi res icon images in frame mode
- Linux: Add JavaFX classpath to launch script
- Linux: add libopenjfx-java dependency to debian package
- Linux: switch swt dependency to suggests

### Caldav:
- Caldav: another NullPointerException fix
- Caldav: fix #694 Null pointer exception writing days of week

### Enhancements:
- Avoid nullpointerexception on missing credentials
- Move isLinux method to Settings
- Revert back to Java 6 build in all cases
- Restore Java 6 compatibility
- Add utility methods in Settings
- Do not try SWT when O365 interactive mode is selected.

### Windows:
- Windows: update winrun4j 64 wrapper to support java > 8, see https://github.com/poidasmith/winrun4j/pull/81

### GUI:
- GUI: dispose notification dialog on close
- GUI: increase default frame size
- GUI: add hi res icon images
- GUI: use setLocationRelativeTo to set frame location

### SWT:
- SWT: O365Interactive is not compatible with SWT, do not try to create SWT tray
- SWT: call GDK.gdk_error_trap_push() to avoid crash
- SWT: Enable debug mode
- SWT: upgrade SWT to 4.9
- SWT: drop deprecated SWT 3 calls and adjust tray icon image to 22px

### Appveyor:
- Appveyor: build with JDK11
- Merge patch #51 Check for javafx in compile classpath
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
