<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.davmail.DavMail.desktop</id>
  <name>DavMail</name>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <summary>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Ever wanted to get rid of Outlook ? DavMail is a
      POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP exchange gateway allowing
      users to use any mail/calendar client (e.g. Thunderbird with
      Lightning or Apple iCal) with an Exchange server, even from the
      internet or behind a firewall through Outlook Web
      Access. DavMail now includes an LDAP gateway to Exchange global
      address book and user personal contacts to allow recipient
      address completion in mail compose window and full calendar
      support with attendees free/busy display. The main goal of
      DavMail is to provide standard compliant protocols in front of
      proprietary Exchange. This means LDAP for address book, SMTP to
      send messages, IMAP to browse messages on the server in any
      folder, POP to retrieve inbox messages only and Caldav for
      calendar support. Thus any standard compliant client can be used
      with Microsoft Exchange. DavMail gateway is implemented in java
      and should run on any platform. Releases are tested on Windows,
      Linux (Ubuntu) and Mac OSX. Tray does not work on MacOS and is
      replaced with a full frame. Tested successfully with the Iphone
      (gateway running on a server).
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://davmail.sourceforge.net</url>
  <url type="donation">https://sourceforge.net/donate/index.php?group_id=184600</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://screenshots.debian.net/screenshots/000/015/485/large.png</image>
      <image>http://davmail.sourceforge.net/images/davmailArchitecture.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0</project_license>
  <developer_name>Mickaël Guessant</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="5.4.0" date="2019-11-11">
      <description>
        <p>
            Bugfix release to fix NTLM authentication for some Exchange on premise instances.
            Also includes a new OSX handlers implementation required to support recent OSX JDKs.

            Main new feature is experimental support for stored Oauth tokens with davmail.oauth.persistToken=true,
            tokens are stored encrypted with client provided password.
            Also improved SPECIAL-USE IMAP support and fixed a few regressions related to ExchangeSessionFactory refactoring
            and a lot of bug fixed from user feedback.

            ###Enhancements:
            - Add sonar target to ant build
            - Sonar configuration
            - Add sonarqube-ant-task to lib
            - Throw NoSuchElementException in message iterator for iteration beyond the end of the collection
            - InterruptedException should not be ignored
            - currentVersion is never null
            - Make AbstractConnection abstract
            - Update default user agent to latest version of Edge on Windows
            - Add .gitignore file
            - Update StringEncryptor to Java 8
            - Update Maven and Ant build to Java 1.8
            - Drop Java 7 in travis config
            - Add {AES} prefix to encrypted strings
            - Improve StringEncryptor compatibility with older jdks
            - Ignore stream errors on disconnect, messages cleanup
            - Testcase for password based string encryptor
            - Implement password based string encryptor
            - Refactor settings save to preserve comments
            - Force Trusty in Travis config

            ###Appveyor:
            - Appveyor: Update to ant 1.10.7
            - Appveyor: test JDK 12 and 13 build

            ###Security:
            - Security: secure XML transformer
            - Security: Untrusted XML should be parsed without resolving external data

            ###SWT:
            - SWT: Refactor the synchronisation mechanism to not use a Thread instance as a monitor

            ###LDAP:
            - LDAP: Add a note to Thunderbird directory config on uid=username syntax

            ###IMAP:
            - IMAP: implement RETURN (SPECIAL-USE) in IMAP list command, return special folders only, fix for https://sourceforge.net/p/davmail/bugs/721
            - IMAP: allow recursive search on public folders

            ###Carddav:
            - Carddav: iOS does not support VCard 4, detect its old Carddav client and send VCard 3 content, exclude unsupported distribution list items

            ###Caldav:
            - Caldav: do not try to send cancel notifications on shared and public calendars

            ###EWS:
            - EWS: allow O365Manual in headless mode
            - EWS: implement command line mode for O365ManualAuthenticator, as suggested in https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/48
            - EWS: exchangecookie is not a good check of successful authentication
            - EWS: detect direct EWS even if mode is different
            - EWS: experimental, store Oauth refresh tokens in davmail.properties when davmail.oauth.persistToken=true
            - EWS: fix /public and /archive folders access over EWS
            - EWS: improve O365Authenticator error detection
            - EWS: fix access to /public folder
            - EWS: Try to improve O365 authentication with ADFS tenants

            ###Documentation:
            - Doc: fix trusterbird link on home page

            ###Linux:
            - Linux: switch spec file to java-1.8.0
            - Linux: prepare rhel8 support

            ###SMTP:
            - SMTP: fix #720 Davmail returns 503 instead of 530 when trying to send mail before authentication
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
