<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.davmail.DavMail.desktop</id>
  <name>DavMail</name>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <summary>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Ever wanted to get rid of Outlook ? DavMail is a
      POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange and Office 365 gateway allowing
      users to use any mail/calendar client (e.g. Thunderbird with
      Lightning or Apple iCal) with an Exchange server, even from the
      internet or behind a firewall through Outlook Web
      Access. DavMail now includes an LDAP gateway to Exchange global
      address book and user personal contacts to allow recipient
      address completion in mail compose window and full calendar
      support with attendees free/busy display. The main goal of
      DavMail is to provide standard compliant protocols in front of
      proprietary Exchange. This means LDAP for address book, SMTP to
      send messages, IMAP to browse messages on the server in any
      folder, POP to retrieve inbox messages only and Caldav for
      calendar support. Thus any standard compliant client can be used
      with Microsoft Exchange. DavMail gateway is implemented in java
      and should run on any platform. Releases are tested on Windows,
      Linux (Ubuntu) and Mac OSX. Tray does not work on MacOS and is
      replaced with a full frame. Tested successfully with the Iphone
      (gateway running on a server).
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://davmail.sourceforge.net</url>
  <url type="donation">https://sourceforge.net/donate/index.php?group_id=184600</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://screenshots.debian.net/screenshots/000/015/485/large.png</image>
      <image>https://davmail.sourceforge.net/images/davmailArchitecture.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0</project_license>
  <developer_name>Mickaël Guessant</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
      <release version="6.3.0" date="2025-02-26">
          Merged some contributions provided by users on github, updated embedded jre to 21 for improved TLS 1.3 support,
          applied documentation fixes, reviewed rpm build to provide el9 compatibility, implemented channel binding for NTLM
          authentication. Also added a more recent Docker file in contribs, worked on GCC high tenants compatibility.
          Microsoft Graph backend implementation is in progress but far from complete.

          ### Caldav
          - Caldav: handle multiple categories on TODO items, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/372
          - Caldav: Merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/386 validate and repair Exchange calendar characters

          ### LDAP
          - LDAP: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/353, fix first certificate selection logic
          - LDAP: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/353 Add support for retrieving user certificates

          ### IMAP
          - IMAP: fix backslash in password quoted string by: Max-Julian Pogner &lt;max-julian@pogner.at&gt;, finalize merge, call new parsing method from nextToken and remove backslash handling in username
          - IMAP: fix backslash in password quoted string by: Max-Julian Pogner &lt;max-julian@pogner.at&gt;, review and switch to ParseException for error handling and chars instead of bytes
          - IMAP: merge unit test for patch fix backslash in password quoted string by: Max-Julian Pogner &lt;max-julian@pogner.at&gt;
          - IMAP: initial merge of patch fix backslash in password quoted string by: Max-Julian Pogner &lt;max-julian@pogner.at&gt;
          - IMAP: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/359, handle RFC822.TEXT

          ### O365
          - O365: add GCC high example settings in default davmail.properties
          - O365: https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/380 Remove trailing slash from O365_LOGIN_URL
          - O365: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/380 Missed one change
          - O365: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/380 Enhance support for the davmail.outlookUrl property setting and fully support GCC-High endpoints
          - O365: implement OneWaySMS MFA prompt, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/134
          - O365: get O365 Login Url from settings for non standard tenants and add additional error use case
          - O365: detect live.com token. Note: may not be enough to make DavMail work with live.com accounts
          - O365: dropping all workaroungs for OpenJFX bugs that should be fixed in recent versions

          ### EWS
          - EWS: experimental, try to implement recurrence count with NumberOfOccurrences, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/373
          - EWS: make settings timezoneid higher priority than mailbox configuration, make encode/decode foldername methods public for graph API

          ### Graph
          - Graph: introduce GRAPH_URL and davmail.loginUrl in Settings
          - Graph: initiate search filter implementation
          - Graph: implement folder recursive search
          - Introduce folderClass
          - Graph: Create folders unit tests
          - Graph: fix folder retrieval by id
          - Graph: initial folder retrieval implementation
          - Graph: compute graph API property id from name and tag
          - Graph: Empty Graph ExchangeSession implementation
          - Graph: prepare graph request builder for graph implementation
          - Graph: Experimental, introduce davmail.enableGraph property to obtain a token compatible with Microsoft Graph API

          ### Linux
          - Linux: fix ant dependency for fedora
          - Linux: davmail.spec to not try to link os provided swt.jar when using embedded one
          - Linux: work on el9 compatibility for RPM build
          - Linux: Embed davmail-user.conf in source package, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/356
          - Linux: Create davmail user/group per new conventions in RPM 4.19, merge changes from https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/356
          - Build: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/346 unable to run jlink on linux
          - Linux: force shutdown with -token option
          - Linux: Add OpenJFX case for Kubuntu

          ### Documentation
          - Doc: update windows build documentation, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/384
          - Doc: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/174 fix docs typo in property davmail.enableKeepAlive
          - Doc: improve documentation on how to run DavMail as a windows service
          - Doc: update documentation for non default tenants (US, China)
          - Doc: provide more information in initial consent for O365 authentication
          - Doc: update FAQ on application registration in Entra ID (Azure AD)
          - Doc: mention AppIndicator and KStatusNotifierItem Support in Fedora setup instructions

          ### Docker
          - Docker: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/381 by SethRobertson Bug 201: Docker support for building and running

          ### NTLM
          - NTLM: remove CIFS dependency
          - NTLM: cleanup code from audit
          - NTLM: use ThreadLocal to manage SecureRandom generators
          - NTLM: switch to DavMailNTLMSchemeFactory to enable channel binding, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/352
          - NTLM: retrieve certificate from http context
          - NTLM: Duplicate of NTLMScheme from HttpClient to implement channel binding
          - NTLM: adjust NTLMEngineImpl to handle channel binding
          - NTLM: Duplicate code from NTLMEngineImpl to implement channel binding

          ### Enhancements
          - Fix from audit
          - Drop web component
          - Drop servlet-api.jar, no longer required
          - Drop deprecated DavGatewayServletContextListener (we no longer provide an embedded war file)
          - Trying to fix custom jre for TLS 1.3, see https://stackoverflow.com/questions/63964939/tls-1-3-handshake-failure-when-using-openjdk-14-java-module-runtime and https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/388
          - fix download-jre for embedded JDK on windows, fetch version 21
          - switch davmail linux launcher to zulu JDK 21 for better TLS 1.3 support
          - switch main package to zulu JDK 21 for better TLS 1.3 support
          - StringUtilTest CRLF => LF, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/378
          - StringUtil CRLF => LF, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/378
          - Security: Enable TLSv1.3 between DavMail and Exchange/O365
          - PKCS11: review SunPKCS11ProviderHandler
          - HttpClient: cleanup from audit
          - svn ignore .idea
          - Downgrade jackrabbit to 2.20.15 for java 8 compatibility
          - Upgrade jackrabbit to 2.21.25 and httpclient to 4.5.14
      </release>
      <release version="6.2.2" date="2024-03-30">
          Includes some build process fixes, use jlink to build a customized jre for standalone package,
          Thunderbird configuration documentation updated with new screenshots.
          Also implemented a new -token command line option to launch O365InteractiveAuthenticator and get an authentication token.

          ### OSX
          - OSX: document how to embed Zulu jre inside DavMail app

          ### Enhancements
          - Fix comment in DavMail shell
          - Detect missing network connectivity during token refresh to avoid invalidating token
          - Upgrade JCIFS to 1.3.19 for NTLM support
          - Cleanup from audit
          - Drop war package from release files, there are more modern ways to run DavMail in server mode without a webapp container
          - From audit: place LOCK.wait in a loop
          - Fix from audit, use try with resource
          - Cleanup from audit, remove deprecated getSubjectDN, getIssuerDN

          ### O365
          - O365: Improve error message on missing add-exports, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/344
          - O365: Refactor manual authentication dialog to clearly separate steps
          - Remove explicit dependency on O365InteractiveAuthenticator for -token option
          - Implement a -token option to launch interactive authenticator and print obtained refresh token, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/338
          - O365: Try to adjust ItemId to 140 length, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/328
          - O365: prepare GCC-High/DoD endpoints support, fix regression
          - O365: prepare GCC-High/DoD endpoints support, move Outlook login url references to Settings
          - O365: prepare GCC-High/DoD endpoints support, move outlook url references to Settings

          ### EWS
          - EWS: Properly set errorDetail on xml stream error to raise exception
          - EWS: disable IS_SUPPORTING_EXTERNAL_ENTITIES to fix xml parsing security warning

          ### Caldav
          - Fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/342 map America/Winnipeg to Central Standard Time
          - Caldav: Fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/337 take timezone into account when looking for excluded occurrence
          - Fix settings implementation, # are allowed in values, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/326

          ### IMAP
          - IMAP: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/339 classcast exception on malformed content

          ### Build
          - Maven: update compiler to 3.10.1
          - Maven: optimize dependencies
          - Maven: exclure httpclient 3 transitive dependency
          - Appveyor: build only master branch
          - Build: use jlink to create a custom jre to reduce embedded jre size

          ### Security
          - Security: fix security alert on Runtime.getRuntime().exec
          - Security: fix security alert on Runtime.getRuntime().exec

          ### Linux
          - Linux: force GTK2 only with SWT
          - Linux: switch to Azul JRE 17 with "davmail azul" command
          - Linux: Enable OpenJFX on Fedora to make O365Interactive work with Java 17 and later

          ### Documentation
          - Doc: update roadmap
          - Doc: Add donation buttons to GitHub main readme page
          - Doc: update Thunderbird documentation messages
          - Update release guide, mvn install file no longer required
          - Doc: update Thunderbird documentation, as requested in https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/294
          - Doc: update documentation for Thunderbird configuration
          - Doc: use COPR badge
          - Doc: update release guide
          - Doc: reference OpenSuse build service and Fedora COPR for RPM based linux distributions
          - Update changes file for https://build.opensuse.org/package/show/home:mguessan:davmail/davmail
      </release>
      <release version="6.2.1" date="2024-01-04">
          <description>
              <p>
                  Most changes are related to build process and rpm packaging for Fedora/RHEL, also includes a few bug fixes on IMAP

                  ### Security
                  - Security: Upgrade commons codec to 1.15

                  ### O365
                  - O365: cleanup from audit
                  - O365: no longer apply the disable integrity check workaround by default, fixed in openjfx
                  - O365: add a warning message on FIDO authentication triggered
                  - O365: allow refresh token persistence without provided password
                  - O365: Merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/236 Changed authentication link log level

                  ### Linux
                  - Linux: refactor spec file for fedora, do not call old init service scripts and compile with openjfx
                  - Linux: Fix systemd condition for fedora in spec file
                  - Linux: Adjust JDK dependencies for RPM build

                  ### Build
                  - AppVeyor: Cleanup
                  - AppVeyor: copy plugin to x86-unicode
                  - AppVeyor: switch to server 2019
                  - Appveyor: investigate java versions
                  - AppVeyor: set ANT_HOME value
                  - AppVeyor: update ant path
                  - AppVeyor: update ant download path
                  - Run Sonar scan under JDK19
                  - Switch Appveyor build to JDK 19
                  - Maven: fix urls from https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/225 by Stefan Weil

                  ### IMAP
                  - IMAP: merge patch from https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/140, return folders including special use folders when query is %
                  - IMAP: implement fetch macro flags, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/314
                  - IMAP: fix APPENDUID value order

                  ### Enhancements
                  - Cleanup from audit
                  - Fix typo
                  - NTLM: improve logging of NTLM negotiation
                  - Update Winrun4J wrappers with commons codec 1.15
              </p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="6.2.0" date="2023-11-05">
          <description>
              <p>
                  Another bugfix release to merge user contributions from GitHub, refactor Linux build, upgrade dependencies and a few IMAP and Caldav fixes.

                  ### Security
                  - Update htmlcleaner to 2.29 cf CVE-2023-34624

                  ### Enhancements
                  - Drop Travis-ci, no longer working for opensource projects
                  - fix quotes from audit
                  - Remove space at end of line +0630=Myanmar Standard Time, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/309
                  - Fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/271, keep line order and comments on settings save
                  - Fix from audit
                  - Maven: convert pom.xml to UTF-8

                  ### IMAP
                  - IMAP: merge fix suggested on https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/298
                  - IMAP: merge according to last comment on https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/239
                  - IMAP: improve bodystructure handling, merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/239
                  - IMAP: implement APPENDUID and advertise UIDPLUS
                  - IMAP: implement APPENDUID and advertise UIDPLUS
                  - IMAP: Prepare uidplus, fetch message after create

                  ### Caldav
                  - Caldav: Fix nullpointer as in https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/303
                  - Caldav: Fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/309 Thunderbird daily sends TZOFFSETTO with optional second value
                  - Caldav: adjust isLightning test to include Thunderbird user agent, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/287

                  ### Linux
                  - Linux: based on https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/290 by Björn Bidar &lt;bjorn.bidar@thaodan.de&gt;, remove svn commit reference in davmail.spec
                  - Remove svn tag from folder name inside source packages
                  - Linux: remove chkconfig from Requires preun and post in davmail.spec as suggested on build.opensuse.org
                  - Linux: dos2unix davmail.changes
                  - Linux: update changelog with Björn Bidar &lt;bjorn.bidar@thaodan.de&gt; contribution from https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/289
                  - Linux: Add back changelog file and convert to OpenSUSE format from https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/289
                  - Linux: Merge changes from https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/290 except %version that may impact release cycle
                  - Linux: convert davmail.spec changelog to OpenSUSE format, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/290
                  - Linux: restore spec file with lf and changelog, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/289
                  - Linux: remove downloaded azul jdk package

                  ### ADFS
                  - ADFS: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/270 by Felix Engelmann, enable ADFS authentication with SAML assertions

                  ### EWS
                  - EWS: Cleanup from audit
                  - EWS: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/299 avoid logging large response message content
                  - EWS: BackOffMilliseconds unit test
                  - EWS: parse BackOffMilliseconds value on throttling

                  ### O365
                  - O365: in O365 interactive, use invokeAndWait on failover to manual to avoid multiple instances of popup window
                  - Upgrade jettison to 1.5.4 in pom.xml
                  - Upgrade jettison to 1.5.4

                  ### Windows
                  - Windows: drop explicit reference to sun.security.mscapi.SunMSCAPI, Windows-MY should be available on all windows JDK

                  ### Documentation
                  - Doc: Update server properties documentation with davmail.oauth.persistToken
                  - Doc: fix link to SonarCloud
              </p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="6.1.0" date="2023-03-19">
          <description>
              <p>
                  First release in a long time to publish pending changes, including Kerberos support fix,
                  experimental number matching support for upcoming Microsoft authenticator default configuration change,
                  store new refresh token received at authentication.
                  In addition, some Log4J specific patches to remove vulnerable classes from library
                  (even if DavMail is not impacted with standard configuration)

                  ### O365
                  - O365: implement number matching logic in O365Authenticator
                  - O365: retrieve number matching value during phone app MFA
                  - O365: adjust logging level on O365 refresh token error
                  - O365: change persist token logic to store new refresh token after succesful refresh
                  - Experimental: store refreshed token when davmail.storeRefreshedToken=true

                  ### Windows
                  - Windows: Add missing labelReplace active wait with wait/notifyAll in DavService
                  - Update winrun4j wrappers after lib upgrades

                  ### Linux
                  - Linux: block davmail azul when davmail script is located under /usr/bin (package installed)
                  - Linux: fix PosixFilePermissions for writeable only by user
                  - Linux: try to make .davmail.properties file readable by user only on create
                  - Linux: improve launch script to take into account script location


                  ### Enhancements
                  - Add missing label
                  - Replace active wait with wait/notifyAll
                  - Upgrade woodstox to 1.4.0 and jettison to 1.5.3
                  - Merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/225 remove (most) http links in Maven POM
                  - Make ScheduledThreadPool thread daemon
                  - Switch to https for version check
                  - DavMailIdleConnectionEvictor fix from audit
                  - Refactor DavMailIdleConnectionEvictor to be less agressive on idle connection checks/purge and use scheduler instead of active polling
                  - Override SPNegoScheme to take into account DavMail kerberos settings

                  ### Documentation
                  - Sample syslog configuration
                  - Update current version in README.md
                  - OSX: remove reference to Growl in documentation
                  - Doc: security note on DavMail not vulnerable to CVE-2021-44228
                  - Doc: add a section on Fedora installation from copr

                  ### Caldav
                  - Caldav: Do not try to update modified occurrences on Mozilla thunderbird dismiss event

                  ### Security
                  - Security: Strip packaged log4j jar from JMSSink and JDBCAppender to ensure DavMail is not vulnerable to CVE-2022-23305 &amp; CVE-2022-23302, see https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/250
                  - Remove JMSAppender, SMTPAppender and SocketServer from Log4J binary as an additional security measure (CVE-2019-17571 CVE-2021-4104), even if DavMail is not vulnerable with standard configuration
                  - Upgrade Log4J to latest version 1.2.17 in Winrun4J wrappers
                  - Upgrade Log4J to latest version 1.2.17
              </p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="6.0.1" date="2021-12-03">
          <description>
              <p>
                  Bugfix release with a few Office 365 enhancements

                  ### O365
                  - O365: default to MSCAPI on windows for native client certificate access
                  - O365: name button Send instead of OK in manual authenticator dialog
                  - OS65: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/158 Added Copy to Clipboard button Manual auth dialog

                  ### Linux
                  - Linux: improve "davmail azul" error handling
                  - Linux: Update changelog in RPM spec
                  - Linux: Fix RPM spec, remote source does not work
                  - Linux: Merge RPM spec contribution from michals on https://build.opensuse.org, check for systemd support and deploy the right service

                  ### HC4
                  - HC4: make DavMail Kerberos configuration provider

                  ### EWS
                  - EWS: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/106 Support servers only offering EWS/Services.wsdl instead of EWS/Exchange.asmx

                  ### Documentation
                  - Doc: Remove HttpClient migration warning
                  - Doc: instructions on standalone setup on Linux for best O365 support
                  - Update readme for GitHub home page
              </p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="6.0.0" date="2021-07-05">
          <description>
              <p>
                  First major release in a long time, main change is switch from HttpClient 3 to 4, please report any regression related to this major rewrite.
                  DavMail now supports more O365 configurations, including access to client certificate to validate device trust.
                  O365 refresh tokens can now be stored securely in a separate (writable) file.
                  On Linux, in order to ensure the right java version is used, a command line option to download latest Azul JRE with OpenJFX support was added,
                  on windows a standalone package contains Azul JRE FX 15, on OSX updated universalJavaApplicationStub to latest version.

                  ### OSX:
                  - OSX: completely drop Growl support
                  - OSX: prepare possible path for an embedded jre mode
                  - OSX: update universalJavaApplicationStub to latest version from https://github.com/tofi86/universalJavaApplicationStub/blob/master/src/universalJavaApplicationStub

                  ### Documentation:
                  - Doc: merge Clarify the usage of imapIdleDelay https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/116
                  - Doc: add comment on IDLE and timeout setting
                  - Doc: link to standalone windows package
                  - Doc: fix Zulu link
                  - Doc: remove references to Java 6 in documentation

                  ### Build:
                  - Appveyor: update ant
                  - Appveyor: build with jdk15
                  - Appveyor: purge artifacts for all builds except jdk 8
                  - Build: run Sonar with JDK 11
                  - Update junit to 4.13.1 in Maven
                  - Update junit to 4.13.1

                  ### Linux:
                  - Linux: Experimental: download Azul JRE FX with command 'davmail azul'
                  - Linux: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/133 Linux Gnome Desktop: fix systray support
                  - Linux: Update service file to allow 0-1023 ports binding (https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/117)


                  ### Windows:
                  - Windows: switch standalone jre to Azul FX 15
                  - Windows: create a standalone package with Azul JRE FX in order to have a working O365InteractiveAuthenticator
                  - Winrun4J: prefer embedded VM for standalone package and export sun.net.www.protocol.https
                  - Winrun4J: update binaries
                  - Winrun4J: prepare standalone configuration
                  - Windows: update winrun4j config to require Java >= 8

                  ### IMAP:
                  - IMAP: fix thread handling from audit
                  - IMAP: Compute body part size with failover

                  ### O365:
                  - O365: log token file creation
                  - O365: cleanup from audit
                  - O365: Add davmail.oauth.tokenFilePath to sample properties file
                  - O365: disable HTTP/2 loader on Java 14 and later to enable custom socket factory
                  - O365: allow user agent override in O365InteractiveAuthenticator, switch default user agent to latest Edge
                  - O365: with Java 15 url with code returns as CANCELLED
                  - O365: MSCAPI and Java version 13 or higher required to access TPM protected client certificate on Windows
                  - O365: merge first commit from https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/134/ OAuth via ADFS with MFA support
                  - O365: fix store refreshToken call
                  - O365: introduce davmail.oauth.tokenFilePath setting to store Oauth tokens in a separate file
                  - O365: switch to try with resource style
                  - Drop explicit dependency to netscape.javascript package in O365InteractiveJSLogger
                  - O365: follow redirects on ADFS authentication

                  ### HC4:
                  - Refactor ExchangeSessionFactory, create HttpClientAdapter in session
                  - HC4: update winrun4j binaries
                  - HC4: drop HttpClient 3 dependency in Maven, winrun4j binaries and nsi setup
                  - HC4: drop remaining HttpClient 3 classes
                  - HC4: drop DavMailCookieSpec and DavGatewaySSLProtocolSocketFactory (merge in SSLProtocolSocketFactory)
                  - HC4: drop DavGatewayHttpClientFacade and RestMethod
                  - HC4: default to Edge user agent
                  - HC4: Do not enable NTLM in Kerberos mode
                  - HC4: switch checkConfig to HttpClient 4
                  - HC4: merge HC4DavExchangeSession to DavExchangeSession
                  - HC4: cleanup HC4ExchangeFormAuthenticator references
                  - HC4: merge HC4ExchangeFormAuthenticator to ExchangeFormAuthenticator, extend authenticator interface to return HttpClientAdapter, switch to DavExchangeSession
                  - HC4: switch O365 authenticators test code to HttpClient 4
                  - HC4: adjust CreateItemMethod chunked call
                  - HC4: switch ExchangeSessionFactory to HttpClient 4
                  - HC4: add a warning about HttpClient 4 migration
                  - HC4: Enable ssl logging in addition to wire with HttpClient 4
                  - HC4: switch EWS implementation to HttpClient 4

                  ### EWS:
                  - EWS: improve isItemId detection to match base 64 encoded id
                  - EWS: drop NTLM as a failover logic
                  - EWS: cleanup unused code now that we have a reliable way to retrieve email address with ConvertId
                  - EWS: drop property davmail.caldavRealUpdate, no longer used
                  - EWS: Improved uid handling from audit
                  - EWS: Enable Woodstox workaround for malformed xml with latest Woodstox version

                  ### Enhancements:
                  - Clear session pool on DavMail restart
                  - Upgrade to Woodstox 6.2.0 as it's now available on debian, drop Woodstox patched StreamScanner

                  ### Caldav:
                  - Caldav: merge https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/139 Fix missing XML encode
                  - Caldav: use Exchange timezone to compute event time in test case
                  - Caldav: create test cases for recurring events
              </p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="5.5.1" date="2019-04-19">
      <description>
          <p>
              Fix regression on domain\username authentication over IMAP and some cleanup

              ### IMAP:
              - IMAP: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/issues/100 regression with domain\username authentication

              ### O365:
              - O365: set jdk.http.ntlm.transparentAuth=allHosts to enable NTLM for ADFS support

              ### Build:
              - dist cleanup
              - Update release guide with Fedora copr instructions
              - Exclude .sonarwork from source package
              - Build: fix release file name
          </p>
      </description>
      </release>
      <release version="5.5.0" date="2019-04-15">
      <description>
        <p>
            This release contains a lot of bugfixes, enhancements and some user contributions from Github.
            Most activity is related to HttpClient 4 refactoring, this will probably be the latest version based in HttpClient 3.
            Minimum Java version is now 8, also dropped Growl support on MacOS.
            Notable changes for end users are Oauth token persistence to avoid frequent O365 authentications and OIDC support for
            personal outlook accounts.
            Known issues: some users reported regressions with form authentication, please report such regressions with log files.

            ### IMAP:
            - IMAP: catch non IOException errors in FolderLoadThread
            - IMAP: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/91 Allow user name to be specified as user@domain.com in addition to domain\user to access shared mailbox
            - IMAP: unquote CHARSET in IMAP search
            - IMAP: cleanup test cases

            ### Documentation:
            - Doc: describe new Office 365 authentication modes
            - Doc: remove deprecated enableEWS reference
            - Doc: Document new connection modes in template davmail.properties
            - Doc: Add all time downloads badge
            - Doc: push sonarcloud badges

            ### Enhancements:
            - Apply xml transformer settings recommended by Sonar
            - dos2unix template davmail.properties file
            - prepare migration to https://davmail.sourceforge.io
            - Settings: cleanup from audit
            - Latest edge user agent does not work, use Outlook 2013 instead
            - Convert HTTP code to Java 8
            - Cleanup from audit
            - Fix sonar detected vulnerability
            - Update to Java 8 and code cleanup
            - Comment HttpURLConnectionWrapper
            - Fix regression in AbstractServer
            - Remove unused label
            - Cleanup from audit at Java 8 language level

            ### Security:
            - Enable TLSv1.1 and TLSv1.2

            ### HttpClient 4:
            - HC4: httpClient is not shared between clients, do not track connection state to enable NTLM connection pooling
            - HC4: set default connection per route to 5
            - HC4: refactor Exchange 2007 test cases
            - HC4: Prepare switch, create a temporary HC4WebDav mode
            - HC4: ExchangeSession cleanup
            - HC4: unit test cleanup
            - HC4: make ExchangeSession independent of HttpClient implementation
            - HC4: remove reference to old HttpStatus in HttpClientAdapter
            - HC4: more HC4ExchangeFormAuthenticator refactoring and fixes
            - HC4: test form authentication failure
            - HC4: more DavExchangeSession refactoring
            - HC4: more form authenticator fixes
            - HC4: create ResponseWrapper interface for PostRequest and GetRequest
            - HC4: new executeFollowRedirect implementation and get user agent from settings
            - HC4: cleanup from audit and fix regression, need to follow redirect after OWA authentication
            - HC4: more authentication test case
            - HC4: Implement single thread connection evictor
            - HC4: improve PostRequest and RestRequest
            - HC4: implement executePostRequest with test case
            - HC4: new GetRequest implementation with test case
            - HC4: more request refactoring
            - Refactor RestRequest to use ResponseHandler mode only
            - Refactor TestHttpClientAdapter
            - HC4: improve RestRequest
            - HC4: remove old HttpException and move to HttpResponseException
            - HC4: switch to HttpGet
            - HC4: add buildHttpException to HttpClientAdapter
            - HC4: cleanup from audit
            - HC4: keep statusLine in request
            - HC4: cleanup to finalize migration
            - HC4: convert encodeAndFixUrl
            - HC4: Remove old HttpStatus dependency
            - Remove HttpException dependency
            - HC4: convert Head and Post methods
            - HC4: convert GetMethod to HttpGet
            - HC4: convert remaining http client 3 methods
            - HC4: Implement create/delete folder
            - HC4: implement Exchange WebDav search request
            - HC4: Fix initial uri in HttpClientAdapter
            - HC4: convert internalGetFolder
            - HC4: refactor TestCaldavHttpClient4
            - HC4: more test cases on session creation
            - HC4: convert getWellKnownFolders, first working version of session creation
            - HC4: convert checkPublicFolder
            - HC4: get httpClientAdapter from HC4ExchangeFormAuthenticator
            - HC4: Main test case for HC4DavExchangeSession
            - HC4: convert getEmailAndAliasFromOptions
            - HC4: convert getMailpathFromWelcomePage
            - HC4: baseline DavExchangeSession for HttpClient 4 migration
            - HTTP: Improve HttpClientAdapter, enable kerberos support according to setting
            - HttpClient4: improve HttpClientAdapter
            - HttpClient4: Test timeouts with proxy
            - Refactor TestHttpClient4 with try with resource

            ### Caldav:
            - Caldav: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/88 EXDATE timezone issue

            ### O365:
            - O365: fix https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/92 failover for null query with non https URI
            - O365: refactor O365Authenticator and fix regressions
            - O365: switch to new executeFollowRedirect implementation
            - O365: refactor O365Authenticator
            - Refactor O365InteractiveJSLogger to work with more JDK versions

            ### Test:
            - Test: improve notification dialog test
            - Test: Improve client certificate test
            - Improve getReleasedVersion test case
            - Test: Improve base test cases
            - Add new harmcrest-core junit dependency ant enable IMAP test cases
            - Test: update junit to 4.12
            - Run a SSL server socket
            - Test: cleanup code
            - Improve TestDavGateway
            - Make AbstractDavMailTestCase abstract
            - HttpClient: improve test cases

            ### Build:
            - Fix file name for Appveyor trunk builds
            - Fix git svn warning
            - try to get svn revision from git
            - Set jacoco path in sonar config
            - fix test-compile language level
            - Upload coverage report to sourceforge for AppVeyor
            - Prepare Jacoco coverage report
            - Cleanup unused ant check
            - Exclude Sonar working directory from package
            - Appveyor: try to run sonar from Appveyor build

            ### EWS:
            - EWS: make getPageSize static
            - EWS: merge PR Allow to configure EWS folder fetch page size https://github.com/mguessan/davmail/pull/79
            - EWS: fix response handling
            - EWS: fix O365Authenticator
            - EWS: fix regression in O365Token
            - EWS: handle malformed id_token
            - EWS: refactor authenticators to use davmail.enableOidc
            - EWS: create a new davmail.enableOidc setting tp switch to new v2.0 OIDC compliant endpoint https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/active-directory/develop/azure-ad-endpoint-comparison
            - EWS: Prepare OIDC support, add v2.0 url in interactive authenticator
            - EWS: Prepare OIDC support, decode id_token
            - EWS: enable davmail.oauth.persistToken by default

            ### DAV:
            - DAV: MOVE returns SC_CONFLICT on missing target folder
            - Dav: Update to Java 8

            ### SMTP:
            - SMTP: improve error message handling
            - SMTP: fix smtp test cases

            ### LDAP:
            - LDAP: clean test case
            - LDAP: fix dn authentication
            - LDAP: Ber code cleanup from audit
            - LDAP: update LdapConnection to Java 8
            - LDAP: make parseIntWithTag protected to call it from LdapConnection
            - Use imported Ber implementation instead of com.sun.jndi.ldap
            - Import Ber implementation from OpenJDK to avoid compilation warnings

            ### OSX:
            - OSX: drop Growl support
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
