<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/CalDav/LDAP Exchange Gateway - Frequently asked questions</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="Frequently asked questions">
            <p>Frequently asked questions on DavMail forums, mailing list or direct email.
            </p>
            <subsection name="Feedback">
                <p>
                    <strong>How do I create a WIRE debug log ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>In DavMail trackers and forums, I often ask for a WIRE debug log. To create this
                    log file, you will need to change DavMail settings under the advanced tab.
                    Set the WIRE logging category to DEBUG level.
                </p>
                <p>You can then reproduce you issue and send the log file to
                    <a href="mailto:mguessan@free.fr">mguessan@free.fr</a>
                </p>
                <p>The davmail.log file is available in DavMail working directory on Unix and Windows,
                    ~/Library/Logs/DavMail/davmail.log on OSX. This default path can be customized with
                    the
                    <code>Log File Path</code>
                    setting.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="General">
                <p>
                    <strong>Authentication fails with invalid user or password message</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Authentication fails with the following message:
                    <code>Authentication failed: invalid user or password, retry with domain\user</code>
                </p>
                <p>Exchange before 2007 expects domain qualified user name, you may not have
                    to provide the domain name on the logon form if javascript is used to add it,
                    but DavMail can not execute javascript. Thus you need to prefix your user name
                    with the Active Directory domain followed by \
                </p>

                <p>
                    <strong>Authentication fails with error in parsing the status line</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Authentication fails with the following message:
                    <code>error in parsing the status line from the response: unable to find line starting with "HTTP"
                    </code>
                </p>
                <p>Your Exchange server expects HTTPS (secured) connections, use https instead of http in
                    OWA url.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Exchange setup">
                <p>
                    <strong>What are the prerequisites on Exchange server side ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>With Exchange 2003, you only need to have access to OWA (Outlook Web Access), Webdav, Address Book
                    and public folders are always available. Unfortunately, this is not the case with Exchange 2007.
                    You must make sure Webdav support is enabled on your server. You can test this by accessing
                    https://mail.company.com/exchange, which should redirect to /owa. Another important service is the
                    galfind (address book) access at /public/?Cmd=galfind
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Is Exchange 2010 supported ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Currently, the answer is no. As Microsoft decided to drop WebDav support in Exchange 2010, DavMail will
                not work with this new version. New Exchange Web Service support compatible with Exchange 2010 is in the
                roadmap, but not yet available.</p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Caldav (calendar)">
                <p>
                    <strong>How do I detect errors in Thunderbird/Lightning calendar ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Unfortunately, Lightning does not provide much feedback of what is going
                    on. To detect errors at this level, you may activate calendar log settings
                    under Tools/Options/Advanced:
                </p>
                <source>
                    calendar.debug.log=true
                    calendar.debug.log.verbose=true
                </source>

                <p>
                    <strong>Invalid notifications</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Lightning 0.9 mail notifications are broken, activate
                    Caldav notifications to outbox instead:
                </p>
                <p>Check the following parameter in Thunderbird, it should be set
                    to true
                </p>
                <source>calendar.caldav.sched.enabled=true</source>

            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Build">
                <p>
                    <strong>How to build DavMail ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>See
                    <a href="build.html">Building DavMail from source</a>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>