<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway - Frequently asked questions</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="Frequently asked questions">
            <p>Frequently asked questions on DavMail forums, mailing list or direct email.
            </p>
            <subsection name="Feedback">
                <p>
                    <strong>How do I create a WIRE debug log ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>In DavMail trackers and forums, I often ask for a WIRE debug log. To create this
                    log file, you will need to change DavMail settings under the Logging tab.
                    Set the WIRE logging category to DEBUG level.
                </p>
                <p>You can then reproduce your issue and send the log file to
                    <a href="mailto:mguessan@free.fr">mguessan@free.fr</a>
                </p>
                <p>The davmail.log file is available in DavMail working directory on Unix and Windows,
                    ~/Library/Logs/DavMail/davmail.log on OSX. This default path can be customized with
                    the
                    <code>Log File Path</code>
                    setting.
                </p>
                <p>Note: on OSX Lion the Library folder is hidden, a simple way to access it is to launch
                Console (Finder, Go to Utilities), right click on davmail.log and choose Reveal in Finder.</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="General">
                <p>
                    <strong>EWS endpoint not available</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Unfortunately, this probably means your Exchange administrators blocked EWS access.</p>
                <p>To check this, try to connect to
                    <code>https://<i>mail.company.com</i>/ews/exchange.asmx
                    </code>
                    in your favorite web browser: you should get an authentication popup. On authentication success,
                    you should get the EWS wsdl definition. If you don't, please contact the Exchange administrators
                    to let them fix the broken Exchange server setup.
                </p>
                <p>Note: Microsoft Outlook 2011 on OSX and native OSX applications also rely on EWS to connect to
                    Exchange. Mobile devices (Android phones, iPhones, Windows mobile) use ActiveSync on a different
                    endpoint.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Authentication fails with invalid user or password message</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Authentication fails with the following message:
                    <code>Authentication failed: invalid user or password, retry with domain\user</code>
                </p>
                <p>Exchange before 2007 expects domain qualified user name, you may not have
                    to provide the domain name on the logon form if javascript is used to add it,
                    but DavMail can not execute javascript. Thus you need to prefix your user name
                    with the Active Directory domain followed by \
                </p>
                <p>Note to Mac users: OSX applications do not like username with backslash, you have to set windows
                    domain name in DavMail advanced settings and use the simple username in client application.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Authentication fails with error in parsing the status line</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Authentication fails with the following message:
                    <code>error in parsing the status line from the response: unable to find line starting with "HTTP"
                    </code>
                </p>
                <p>Your Exchange server expects HTTPS (secured) connections, use https instead of http in
                    OWA url.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Exchange RSA two factor authentication form</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Exchange now supports two factor authentication for RSA tokens. This requires two potentially
                    different user names in fields userid and username. Use a pipe in client to provide both values:
                    <code>userid|username</code>. In some cases you will need to also provide domain name:
                    <code>userid|domain\username</code>, do not set default windows domain name.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Where can I find DavMail settings file ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>The default location for DavMail settings is a file named .davmail.properties in user home
                    folder. This file is hidden under Linux and OSX. On windows, the user home folder is under
                    <code>Document and Settings</code>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>How to run multiple instances of DavMail ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Just create multiple configuration files and provide them as a command line option, see previous
                    question:
                </p>
                <source>
davmail server1.properties
davmail server2.properties
                </source>

            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Exchange setup">
                <p>
                    <strong>What are the prerequisites on Exchange server side ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>With Exchange 2003, you only need to have access to OWA (Outlook Web Access), Webdav, Address Book
                    and public folders are always available. Unfortunately, this is not the case with Exchange 2007.
                    You must make sure Webdav support is enabled on your server. You can test this by accessing
                    https://mail.company.com/exchange, which should redirect to /owa. Another important service is the
                    galfind (address book) access at /public/?Cmd=galfind
                </p>
                <p>Additional information for Exchange administrators to enable WebDav:</p>
                <p>After running through the pre-requisite checker for each server (Front End CAS server and
                    Back End Mailbox server) and adding the appropriate roles and features, add the following
                    via the ServerManager:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Select the IIS role, then add Role Services</li>
                    <li>Add WebDav Publishing (both Cas server and Mailbox Server)</li>
                    <li>On the Mailbox server, add the ISAPI extensions Role Service to the IIS role</li>
                    <li>On the Default Web Site (each server), enable WebDav</li>
                    <li>Should not have to enable any additional WebDav rules</li>
                    <li>Install the server roles</li>
                    <li>Create a test mailbox (see Exchange Docs)</li>
                </ul>
                <p>To Test:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Ensure that Outlook Web Access works by using the https://<i>exchangeServer</i>/owa URL
                    </li>
                    <li>Try using the pass through legacy URL: https://<i>exchangeServer</i>/exchange,
                        if you receive an error 500 “Internal Server Error”, then WebDav is not working.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    <strong>Is Exchange 2010 supported ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>As Microsoft decided to drop WebDav support in Exchange 2010, I had to implement a new backend from
                    scratch to support the new Exchange Web Services interface. This support is still experimental,
                    but is working quite well. However, you still need to enable it manually in .davmail.properties
                    with the following line:
                    <br/>
                    <source>davmail.enableEws=true</source>
                    <br/>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Is DavMail based on Outlook protocol ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Outlook anywhere uses MAPI RPC over HTTPS to access company LAN through the firewall.
                    DavMail does not use MAPI at all but relies on WebDav (Exchange 2003/2007) or EWS (Exchange
                    2007/2010) to access Exchange. This means you need direct access over HTTPS to either the OWA WebDav
                    url (/exchange/mail@company.com) or EWS (/ews/exchange.asmx) to access Exchange with DavMail.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="OSX">
                <p>
                    <strong>How do I make DavMail start automatically ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Add DavMail.app to "Login Items", see
                    <a href="http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?path=Mac/10.6/en/15189.html">
                        Opening items automatically when you log in
                    </a>
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Linux">
                <p>
                    <strong>Why do I get black on black notifications on Ubuntu ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>This is an SWT bug, upgrade to SWT 3.6, see
                    <a href="https://sourceforge.net/tracker/?func=detail&amp;atid=909904&amp;aid=3138023&amp;group_id=184600">
                        On Ubuntu, notify text conflicts with default theme.
                    </a>
                    http://users.ox.ac.uk/~richardc/guides/LinuxNexus.html
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>DavMail hangs on 64-bit Linux</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Disable use system proxies option in DavMail settings
                </p>
            </subsection>


            <subsection name="Security">
                <p>
                    <strong>How do I secure DavMail connections ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Communication between DavMail and your Exchange server is secured by default as long as you access
                    OWA over HTTPS.
                </p>
                <p>Communication between the messaging client and DavMail is
                    <em>not</em>
                    secured by default. This is not an issue in standalone mode as all communication is local, but you
                    may want to improve this in server (shared) mode.
                </p>
                <p>This is quite simple: you just need to get a server certificate in PKCS12 or JKS format and add it in
                    the key store section in DavMail settings, see&#x20;<a href="sslsetup.html">SSL Setup</a>.
                </p>

                <p>
                    <strong>Are my credentials safe ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>DavMail does not store Exchange username or password, they are provided by the messaging client over
                    IMAP, HTTP, POP, SMTP or LDAP
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Caldav (calendar)">
                <p>
                    <strong>How do I detect errors in Thunderbird/Lightning calendar ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Unfortunately, Lightning does not provide much feedback of what is going
                    on. To detect errors at this level, you may activate calendar log settings
                    under Tools/Options/Advanced:
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[calendar.debug.log=true
calendar.debug.log.verbose=true]]></source>

                <p>
                    <strong>Invalid notifications</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Lightning 0.9 mail notifications are broken, activate
                    Caldav notifications to outbox instead:
                </p>
                <p>Check the following parameter in Thunderbird, it should be set to true
                </p>
                <source>calendar.caldav.sched.enabled=true</source>

                <p>
                    <strong>Public calendars</strong>
                </p>
                <p>To access public folders in Lightning, the URL scheme is:
                </p>
                <source>http://localhost:<i>1080</i>/public/<i>path/to/calendar</i></source>
                <p>To access public folders in iCal, the URL scheme is:
                </p>
                <source>http://localhost:<i>1080</i>/principals/public/<i>path/to/calendar</i></source>
                <p>Note: iCal does not support folder names with spaces or special characters</p>

                <p>
                    <strong>Shared calendars</strong>
                </p>
                <p>To access a shared calendar in Lightning, the URL scheme is:
                </p>
                <source>http://localhost:<i>1080</i>/users/<i>user@company.com</i></source>
                <p>To access a shared calendar in iCal, the URL scheme is:
                </p>
                <source>http://localhost:<i>1080</i>/principals/users/<i>user@company.com</i></source>

            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Mail">
                <p>
                    <strong>Timeout errors during IMAP sync (broken pipe)</strong>
                </p>
                <p>If you Exchange server is too slow, you may get timeout errors during
                    message fetch.
                </p>
                <p>To fix the problem in OSX Mail, go to your account setup under preferences.
                    On the IMAP account having difficulty, go to the advanced tab. Where it says
                    "keep copies for offline viewing", change it to "only messages I've read" or
                    don't keep copies at all.
                </p>
                <p>Under Thunderbird, you can try to change IMAP timeout values
                    (
                    <code>mail.server.server<em>index</em>.timeout
                    </code>
                    and&#x20;<code>mailnews.tcptimeout</code>) or avoid full
                    mailbox sync: disable global search and indexer under advanced options and change
                    Synchronization &amp; Storage options under Account Settings.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Message deleted over IMAP still visible through OWA</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Message move does not exist in IMAP, thus the move is a copy followed by a delete.
                    And a delete is not immediate with IMAP: you need to EXPUNGE the folder to actually
                    delete a message.
                </p>
                <p>A workaround with Thunderbird is to set the property
                    <code>mail.imap.expunge_after_delete=true</code>
                </p>
                <p>New: a new setting is available in DavMail to delete messages immediately over IMAP:
                    <code>davmail.imapAutoExpunge=true</code>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Duplicate messages in Sent folder</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Messages sent through DavMail appear twice in Sent folder when the IMAP client is setup
                    to store sent messages on the server as Exchange already saves sent messages in this folder.
                    Change IMAP client settings or change Save in Sent option in DavMail settings to avoid this issue.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Sent messages encoding issue with Thunderbird</strong>
                </p>
                <p>If special characters appear replaced with ? in sent messages, set
                    <code>mail.strictly_mime</code>
                    advanced option.
                    Go to Tools/Options/Advanced/General/Config Editor and look for a preference
                    with name<code>mail.strictly_mime</code>, set value to
                    <code>true</code>
                    to send messages as quoted-printable.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Access another user mailbox</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Either set base IMAP path in client settings to <code>/users/otheruser@company.com</code> or use the following username:
                    <code>domain\user\otheruser@company.com</code> where otheruser@company.com it target mailbox
                    name.
                </p>

            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Build">
                <p>
                    <strong>How to build DavMail ?</strong>
                </p>
                <p>See
                    <a href="build.html">Building DavMail from source</a>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>