<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway - Linux setup</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="DavMail Setup on linux">
            <subsection name="Standalone setup">
                <p>Prerequisite: Latest OpenJDK with OpenJFX support for best O365 support.
                    Download of latest Azul FX now included in latest davmail script.
                    If SWT is available it provides an improved tray icon (incompatible with O365Interactive mode).
                    If you do not want any tray icon run DavMail with the <code>-notray</code> option.
                </p>

                <p>Download the the platform independent package from Sourceforge and uncompress it with
                    your favorite tool. If you want improved SWT tray icon add the appropriate SWT library in lib
                    folder from <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/swt/">http://www.eclipse.org/swt/</a>, e.g.
                    swt-4.9-gtk-linux-x86_64.jar
                </p>
                <code>unzip davmail-<em>version</em>.zip</code>

                <p>Run <code>./davmail azul</code> once to fetch latest Azul JRE FX.
                </p>

                <p>Just run <code>./davmail</code> to launch DavMail.
                    You should now see the DavMail gateway icon in the tray :
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img align="middle" src="images/ubuntutray.png" alt=""/>
                </div>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Debian package">
                <p>This page describes DavMail setup as a graphical application, if you don't want or need a user interface you can run
                    <a href="serversetup.html">DavMail in server mode</a>
                </p>
                <p>Download current debian package from Sourceforge, double click on it
                    to launch package installer.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Select Install Package, installer will automatically download and
                    install Java and the appropriate SWT package. After installation,
                    DavMail is available in the Applications menu.
                </p>
                <p>In order to run DavMail with systray on Ubuntu 18, you need:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Top icons and appindicator:<code>sudo apt-get install gnome-shell-extension-top-icons gnome-shell-extension-appindicator gnome-tweak-tool</code></li>
                    <li>Enable both in Tweaks</li>
                    <li>Then run DavMail: <code>XDG_CURRENT_DESKTOP= &amp;&amp; davmail</code></li>
                </ul>
                <p>Update for Ubuntu Unity users, you can install Indicator SystemtrayUnity:
                <a href="http://www.webupd8.org/2015/05/on-demand-system-tray-for-ubuntu.html">
                    http://www.webupd8.org/2015/05/on-demand-system-tray-for-ubuntu.html
                </a></p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 14 users, you can restore systray by following instructions at:
                <a href="http://www.webupd8.org/2013/05/how-to-get-systray-whitelist-back-in.html">How to whitelist all systray apps in Ubuntu 14.04 or 14.10 (with Unity)</a></p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 13 users, you will need to apply the following patch to fix missing whitelist
                regression: <a href="https://launchpad.net/~timekiller/+archive/unity-systrayfix">Unity Desktop with Systray Whitelisting Support</a></p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 12 Natty users: they eventually fixed Oneiric issue, use gsettings command below</p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 11.10 Oneiric users: Unity does not support system tray defined by FreeDesktop, you will need
                to switch to standard Gnome Panel to use DavMail (and any other application using system tray)</p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 10.04 users: all tray icons are hidden by default, use the following command to restore normal mode:</p>
                <code>gsettings set com.canonical.Unity.Panel systray-whitelist "['all']"</code>
                <p>If it still does not work, launch DavMail with notray option:</p>
                <code>davmail -notray</code>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Settings">
                <p>Adjust DavMail settings :
                    <a href="gettingstarted.html">Getting started</a>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>