<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway - Linux setup</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="DavMail Setup on linux">
            <subsection name="Standalone setup">
                <p>Prerequisite: Latest OpenJDK from standard distribution repository or installed locally
                </p>
                <p>For interactive authentication two different options are now supported:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>SWT: if Eclipse SWT is available, DavMail will use SWT browser support to obtain O365
                    authentication token. This is based on your native installed browser.</li>
                    <li>OpenJFX: requires a JDK with OpenJFX support, embedded browser is based on webkit.</li>
                </ul>

                <p>Tray icon support: due to various bugs with recent Plasma / Wayland, tray icon is now disabled
                    by default. To enable tray icon support, run DavMail with <code>-tray</code> option or change
                    option in settings.
                </p>

                <ul>
                    <li>Download the platform independent package from Sourceforge and uncompress it with
                        your favorite tool <code>unzip davmail-<em>version</em>.zip</code>
                    </li>
                    <li>Fetch Azul JDK with OpenJFX support: <code>./davmail azul</code></li>
                    <li>Fetch SWT for your architecture: <code>./davmail swt</code></li>
                    <li>Run DavMail: <code>./davmail [davmail.properties]</code></li>
                </ul>

            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Debian package">
                <p>This page describes DavMail setup as a graphical application, if you don't want or need a user interface you can run
                    <a href="serversetup.html">DavMail in server mode</a>
                </p>
                <p>Note: there is an official Debian package for DavMail, see
                    <a href="https://packages.debian.org/fr/sid/davmail">https://packages.debian.org/fr/sid/davmail</a>.
                    However, the latest version may not be available in your distribution, in that case this project
                    provided package is an option, it comes with embedded dependencies.
                </p>
                <p>Download current debian package from Sourceforge, double-click on it
                    to launch package installer.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Select Install Package, installer will automatically download and
                    install Java and the appropriate SWT package. After installation,
                    DavMail is available in the Applications menu.
                </p>
                <p>In order to run DavMail with systray on Ubuntu 18, you need:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Top icons and appindicator:<code>sudo apt-get install gnome-shell-extension-top-icons gnome-shell-extension-appindicator gnome-tweak-tool</code></li>
                    <li>Enable both in Tweaks</li>
                    <li>Then run DavMail: <code>XDG_CURRENT_DESKTOP= &amp;&amp; davmail</code></li>
                </ul>
                <p>On recent Ubuntu versions with Gnome, AppIndicator and KStatusNotifierItem is required for tray icon support</p>
                <p>Update for Ubuntu Unity users, you can install Indicator SystemtrayUnity:
                    <a href="http://www.webupd8.org/2015/05/on-demand-system-tray-for-ubuntu.html">
                        http://www.webupd8.org/2015/05/on-demand-system-tray-for-ubuntu.html
                    </a></p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 14 users, you can restore systray by following instructions at:
                    <a href="http://www.webupd8.org/2013/05/how-to-get-systray-whitelist-back-in.html">How to whitelist all systray apps in Ubuntu 14.04 or 14.10 (with Unity)</a></p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 13 users, you will need to apply the following patch to fix missing whitelist
                    regression: <a href="https://launchpad.net/~timekiller/+archive/unity-systrayfix">Unity Desktop with Systray Whitelisting Support</a></p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 12 Natty users: they eventually fixed Oneiric issue, use gsettings command below</p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 11.10 Oneiric users: Unity does not support system tray defined by FreeDesktop, you will need
                    to switch to standard Gnome Panel to use DavMail (and any other application using system tray)</p>
                <p>Note to Ubuntu 10.04 users: all tray icons are hidden by default, use the following command to restore normal mode:</p>
                <code>gsettings set com.canonical.Unity.Panel systray-whitelist "['all']"</code>
                <p>If it still does not work, launch DavMail with notray option:</p>
                <code>davmail -notray</code>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Fedora">
                <p>Latest released package is available on build.opensuse.org and Fedora COPR</p>

                <p>On Fedora or Centos, enable COPR repository and install DavMail package:
                    <code>
                        dnf copr enable mguessan/davmail
                        dnf install davmail
                    </code>
                </p>

                <p>Tray icon support is not available by default on Fedora with Gnome desktop.
                    You can run DavMail in window mode or install
                    <a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/615/appindicator-support/">
                        AppIndicator and KStatusNotifierItem Support</a>
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Settings">
                <p>Adjust DavMail settings :
                    <a href="gettingstarted.html">Getting started</a>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>
