<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway - macOS setup</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="DavMail Setup on Mac OS X">
            <p>DavMail requires a recent Java JRE, with OpenJFX support for O365Interactive authentication.</p>
            <p>Recommended source is Azul at: <a
                    href="https://www.azul.com/downloads/?version=java-25-lts&amp;os=macos&amp;package=jdk-fx#zulu">Download
                Azul JDK</a>.
                Pick your architecture, ARM for Apple Silicon and x86 64 for intel-based Macs.
            </p>
            <p>An alternative is to use SDKMAN to install java, see <a href="https://sdkman.io/jdks/zulu/">SDKMAN Zulu</a>
                <code>sdk install java 25.0.3.fx-zulu</code>
            </p>
            <p>Next download
                <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/davmail/files/">DavMail-MacOSX-<em>version</em>.app.zip
                </a>
            </p>
            <p>This application bundle is built from source with ant. However, to avoid the apple tax, the
                package is not signed. On recent macOS versions you will get a security warning and a suggestion to move
                application to trash. Just open settings / Privacy &amp; Security, find the message:
                "DavMail was blocked from use because it is not from an identified developer" and click
                <code>Open Anyway</code>
            </p>
            <p>On older OSX Mountain Lion, you need to disable Gatekeeper (at least temporarily) to avoid the
                warning or <code>DavMail is damaged and can’t be opened</code> message with Java 6 package.
            </p>

            <p>Download DavMail macOS package from Sourceforge:
            </p>
            <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                <img src="images/osxdownload.png" alt="OSX Download"/>
            </div>
            <p>Safari should automatically extract application from archive. If not, just
                double-click on the zip file to trigger decompression. DavMail.app directory is then recognized as a
                valid OSX application. However, as the application is not signed, you will need to bypass warning
                under Privacy &amp; Security.
            </p>
            <p>On OSX Mountain Lion, open System Preferences and choose
                Security and Privacy, then unlock panel with lock icon and choose Anywhere:
            </p>
            <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                <img src="images/osxgatekeeper.png" alt="OSX Gatekeeper"/>
            </div>
            <p>Launch DavMail application once (double-click on the application icon).</p>
            <p>You can then go back to System Preferences/Security and Privacy and restore original setting.
            </p>
            <p>On first start the application displays the Settings (Preferences) frame.
            </p>
            <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                <img src="images/osxdesktop.jpg" alt="OSX Desktop"/>
            </div>
            <p>Growl is no longer supported.</p>
            <p>Adjust DavMail settings:
                <a href="gettingstarted.html">Getting started</a>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Troubleshooting">
            <p>If macOS is unable to find you JDK/JRE, check java version in a terminal:
            <code>java -version</code>.
                If you get the following message:
                <code>The operation couldn’t be completed. Unable to locate a Java Runtime.</code>
                you need to reference your version of java for the system wrappers:
                <code>sudo ln -sfn /path/to/your/jdk /Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/yourjdk.jdk</code>
            </p>
            <p>If you chose the zip or tar.gz package, you may also want to set JAVA_HOME and add
                <code>$JAVA_HOME/bin</code> to your PATH.
            </p>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>