<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav Exchange Gateway - OSX IMAP Mail setup</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="OSX IMAP Mail setup">
            <p>There are two ways to access Exchange emails through DavMail Gateway: the good old
                and efficient POP protocol, limited to Inbox access and the IMAP protocol that enables
                full message folder tree access. IMAP support in DavMail is more recent and less optimised
                than POP. This page describes OSX IMAP Mail setup.
            </p>

            <section name="Create a new account">
                <p>Launch Apple Mail, open Preferences and click the plus button to create a new
                account. Enter you full name, email address and password:</p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap1.png"/>
                </div>

                <p>Choose IMAP account type, enter description, DavMail gateway address (localhost).
                    Check username and password:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap2.png"/>
                </div>

                <p>Click continue, if DavMail is not listening on the default IMAP port (143), you
                    will get the following error message, click Continue again to proceed:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap3.png"/>
                </div>

                <p>Leave SSL unchecked and click Continue:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap4.png"/>
                </div>

                <p>Enter Outgoing Mail Server (SMTP) description and DavMail gateway address (localhost).
                    Check Use Authentication and enter your Exchange username and password:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap5.png"/>
                </div>

                <p>Click continue, if DavMail is not listening on the default SMTP port (25), you
                    will get the following error message, click Continue again to proceed:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap6.png"/>
                </div>

                <p>Leave SSL unchecked and click Continue:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap7.png"/>
                </div>

                <p>Check summary and click Create:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap8.png"/>
                </div>

            </section>
            <section name="Additional settings">
                <p>Open the Mailbox Behaviors tab and uncheck Store sent messages on server, as Exchange already
                    stores each sent message in this folder:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap9.png"/>
                </div>
                <p>Under the advanced tab, enter actual DavMail IMAP port:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap10.png"/>
                </div>
                <p>Under the Account Information tab, choose Edit Server List in Outgoing Mail Server (SMTP) field:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap11.png"/>
                </div>
                <p>Open the advanced tab, check use custom port and enter actual DavMail SMTP port:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap12.png"/>
                </div>
                <p>You may also want to set the Add invitations to iCal parameter to Never:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/osxMailImap13.png"/>
                </div>
            </section>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>