<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway - Thunderbird mail setup</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="IMAP Thunderbird mail setup">
            <p>There are two ways to access Exchange emails through DavMail Gateway: the good old
                and efficient POP protocol, limited to Inbox access and the IMAP protocol that enables
                full message folder tree access. DavMail IMAP listener has a higher memory footprint.
            </p>

            <p>This page describes IMAP setup, if you don't need multiple folders access, proceed to
                <a href="thunderbirdmailsetup.html">
                    POP Thunderbird mail setup
                </a>
                instead.
            </p>

            <p>DavMail can be used with any IMAP/SMTP client by adjusting the following description designed for
                Thunderbird. DavMail IMAP support is tested with Thunderbird, Outlook and Apple Mail.
            </p>

            <subsection name="Create a new account">
                <p>Choose <code>Add Mail Account...</code> under Account settings and enter name, email address
                    and password:</p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbirdAccount1.png" alt=""/>
                </div>
                <p>Click <code>Continue</code> and <code>Manual config</code> without waiting for automatic config:</p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbirdAccount2.png" alt=""/>
                </div>

                <p>Incoming server type is IMAP, server hostname is localhost, default port is 1143, no SSL and normal
                    password authentication. Outgoing server is localhost, default port is 1025, no SSL and normal
                    password authentication. Set your username (windows account name or email address) and click
                    <code>Re-test</code> to validate account settings, then <code>Create Account</code>:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbirdAccount3.png" alt=""/>
                </div>


                <p>Without SSL you will get the following warning, check box and confirm account creation:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbirdAccount4.png" alt=""/>
                </div>
                <p>Note: as communication between Thunderbird and DavMail is local, cleartext mode is not an issue,
                    except on shared machines (e.g. Terminal server).</p>

                <p>Proceed to
                    <a href="thunderbirdcalendarsetup.html">Thunderbird calendar setup</a>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

        <section name="Optional additional step">
            <subsection name="Thunderbird mail message tags">
                <p>In Thunderbird email messages can be organized with message tags. Outlook provides
                    similar functionality with categories. DavMail's IMAP gateway can transparently
                    translate tags to categories (and vice versa). For custom defined tags it may be
                    necessary to tell DavMail how to convert tags to categories.
                </p>

                <p>Thunderbird stores tags on the server using IMAP keywords. But internally
                    Thunderbird uses a mapping between the user visible tag names and the
                    actually used keywords. For instance, the <strong>To Do</strong> tag is represented by
                    the <strong>$label4</strong> keyword. Assuming you want the Outlook categories to have the
                    same names as the Thunderbird tags, DavMail must know which keywords
                    Thunderbird uses for each tag.
                </p>

                <p>The keywords used by Thunderbird can be found through Preferences -&gt;
                    Advanced -%gt; Config Editor, and searching for <code>mailnews.tags.*.tag</code>,
                    which will show them as <code>mailnews.tags.<i>keyword</i>.tag</code> settings
                    with their corresponding <i>tag</i> user visible value.
                </p>

                <p>Some default tags are defined in Thunderbird, for which DavMail uses a
                    default mapping to categories:
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[
$label1=Important
$label2=Work
$label3=Personal
$label4=To Do
$label5=Later]]>
                </source>

                <p>These mappings can be overridden and extended by manually adding properties to the
                    DavMail settings file (<code>.davmail.properties</code>) as
                    <code>davmail.imapFlags.<i>keyword</i>=<i>category</i></code>, like this:
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[
davmail.imapFlags.$label2=Hobby
davmail.imapFlags.some_test_tag=Some test Category]]>
                </source>

            </subsection>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>