<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway - Thunderbird mail setup</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="Thunderbird mail setup">
            <p>DavMail supports both IMAP and POP protocols. Most users choose IMAP to have full mailbox access,
                as POP is limited to inbox folder only.
            </p>

            <p>POP protocol is designed to retrieve messages from server and let the client manage storage/folder
                organization locally. All POP delete orders will move messages to server trash folder.
                In order to avoid quota issues on server, DavMail can automatically purge oldest messages from trash
                and sent folders.
            </p>

            <p>DavMail can be used with any IMAP/SMTP client by adjusting the following description designed for
                Thunderbird. DavMail IMAP support is tested with Thunderbird, Outlook and Apple Mail.
            </p>

            <subsection name="Create a new account">
                <p>For a new Thunderbird instance, new account wizard opens on first launch. If you already have
                    existing accounts open <code>Tools/Account settings</code> then
                    <code>Account Actions/Add Mail Account...</code></p>
                <p>Enter name, email address and password and click configure manually:</p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbird/thunderbirdAccount1.png" alt=""/>
                </div>

                <p>Incoming server type is IMAP, server hostname is localhost, default port is 1143, no SSL and normal
                    password authentication. Outgoing server is localhost, default port is 1025, no SSL and normal
                    password authentication. Set your username (windows account name or email address) and click
                    <code>Re-test</code> to validate account settings, then <code>Done</code>:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbird/thunderbirdAccount2.png" alt=""/>
                </div>

                <p>By default local communication between Thunderbird and DavMail is not encrypted, and you get the
                    following warning, check I understand the risks and confirm account creation:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbird/thunderbirdAccount3.png" alt=""/>
                </div>
                <p>Proceed with authentication is you have interactive mode enabled.
                    Initial mail configuration is then complete.</p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbird/thunderbirdAccount4.png" alt=""/>
                </div>

                <p>Proceed to
                    <a href="thunderbirdcalendarsetup.html">Thunderbird calendar setup</a>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

        <section name="Optional additional step">
            <subsection name="Thunderbird mail message tags">
                <p>In Thunderbird email messages can be organized with message tags. Outlook provides
                    similar functionality with categories. DavMail's IMAP gateway can transparently
                    translate tags to categories (and vice versa). For custom defined tags it may be
                    necessary to tell DavMail how to convert tags to categories.
                </p>

                <p>Thunderbird stores tags on the server using IMAP keywords. But internally
                    Thunderbird uses a mapping between the user visible tag names and the
                    actually used keywords. For instance, the <strong>To Do</strong> tag is represented by
                    the <strong>$label4</strong> keyword. Assuming you want the Outlook categories to have the
                    same names as the Thunderbird tags, DavMail must know which keywords
                    Thunderbird uses for each tag.
                </p>

                <p>The keywords used by Thunderbird can be found through Preferences -&gt;
                    Advanced -%gt; Config Editor, and searching for <code>mailnews.tags.*.tag</code>,
                    which will show them as <code>mailnews.tags.<i>keyword</i>.tag</code> settings
                    with their corresponding <i>tag</i> user visible value.
                </p>

                <p>Some default tags are defined in Thunderbird, for which DavMail uses a
                    default mapping to categories:
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[
$label1=Important
$label2=Work
$label3=Personal
$label4=To Do
$label5=Later]]>
                </source>

                <p>These mappings can be overridden and extended by manually adding properties to the
                    DavMail settings file (<code>.davmail.properties</code>) as
                    <code>davmail.imapFlags.<i>keyword</i>=<i>category</i></code>, like this:
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[
davmail.imapFlags.$label2=Hobby
davmail.imapFlags.some_test_tag=Some test Category]]>
                </source>

            </subsection>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>