<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>DavMail POP/IMAP/SMTP/Caldav/Carddav/LDAP Exchange Gateway - Thunderbird mail setup</title>
        <author email="mguessan@free.fr">Mickael Guessant</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="POP Thunderbird mail setup">
            <p>There are two ways to access Exchange emails through DavMail Gateway: the good old
                and efficient POP protocol, limited to Inbox access and the IMAP protocol that enables
                full message folder tree access. IMAP support in DavMail is more recent and less optimised
                than POP.
            </p>

            <p>This page describes POP3 setup, if you need multiple folders access, proceed to
                <a href="thunderbirdimapmailsetup.html">
                    IMAP Thunderbird mail setup
                </a>
                instead.
            </p>

            <p>DavMail can be used with any POP3/SMTP client by adjusting the following description designed for
                Thunderbird
            </p>

            <subsection name="Create a new account">
                <p>Choose <code>Add Mail Account...</code> under Account settings and enter name, email address
                    and password:</p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbirdAccount1.png" alt=""/>
                </div>

                <p>Click <code>Continue</code> and <code>Manual config</code> without waiting for automatic config:</p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbirdAccount2.png" alt=""/>
                </div>

                <p>Incoming server type is POP, server hostname is localhost, default port is 1110, no SSL and normal
                    password authentication. Outgoing server is localhost, default port is 1025, no SSL and normal
                    password authentication. Set your username (windows account name or email address) and click
                    <code>Re-test</code> to validate account settings, then <code>Create Account</code>:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbirdAccount3.png" alt=""/>
                </div>


                <p>Without SSL you will get the following warning, check box and confirm account creation:
                </p>
                <div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
                    <img src="images/thunderbirdAccount4.png" alt=""/>
                </div>
                <p>Note: as communication between Thunderbird and DavMail is local, cleartext mode is not an issue,
                    except on shared machines (e.g. Terminal server).</p>

                <p>Proceed to
                    <a href="thunderbirdcalendarsetup.html">Thunderbird calendar setup</a>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>